Nature Conservancy in Arizona records, 1884-1999
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Nature Conservancy in Arizona records, 1884-1999
MS 408
Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter.
The Nature Conservancy in Arizona records (1884-1999) documents the activities of the Arizona Chapter of The Nature Conservancy, an international non-profit conservation organization dedicated to protecting rare plants and animals and the land and water they need to survive.
14.0 linear feet (approximately 28,000 items)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Nature Conservancy in Arizona is the Arizona Chapter of The Nature Conservancy, an international non-profit conservation organization dedicated to protecting rare plants and animals and the land and water they need to survive. Its mission is to find, protect, and maintain the best examples of rare species and biological communities in the natural world. The Arizona Chapter of The Nature Conservancy, established in 1966, is committed to protecting this natural diversity by partnering with public agencies and private landowners to create and manage a statewide system of natural preserves that protects valuable habitat for Arizona's vanishing wildlife. This system of managed preserves includes: Hassayampa River Preserve, Hartwell Canyon Preserve, Hart Prairie Preserve, Aravaipa Canyon Preserve, Muleshoe Ranch Cooperative Management Area, Ramsey Canyon Preserve, Canelo Hills Cienega Preserve and Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Preserve. To date, The Nature Conservancy in Arizona has helped to protect more than 1.5 million acres of ecologically important land in the state. The organization has been instrumental in affecting changes in state trust land policy and federal legislation for the conservation of special areas and water resources The Conservancy has also initiated bi-national cooperative conservation efforts with Mexico to protect key areas such as Los Fresnos Ranch in Sonora, Mexico, which is an important freshwater source for the San Pedro River in Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into 2 subgroups. Subgroup 1, The Nature Conservancy in Arizona, Chapter Materials, contains five series: Administration, Correspondence, Communications, Program, and Research and Reference files. Subgroup 2, Site Files, contains forty-two series arranged alphabetically by site name.
Subgroup 1: The Nature Conservancy in Arizona, Chapter Materials, 1962-1999
Series 1: Administration, 1970-1997
Series 2: Correspondence, 1964-1999
Series 3: Communications, 1968-1997
Series 4: Program Files, 1975-1998
Series 5: Research and Reference, 1962-1996
Subgroup 2: Site Files, 1884-1998
Series 1: Appleton-Whittell Research Ranch Sanctuary, 1972-1996
Series 2: Aravaipa Canyon Preserve, 1949-1993
Series 3: Arivaca Creek, 1978-1989
Series 4: Baboquivari Mountains Macrosite, 1969-1984
Series 5: Bill Williams River Megasite, 1975-1994
Series 6: Buenos Aires National Wildlife Refuge, 1982-1992
Series 7: Canelo Hills Cienega Preserve, 1967-1993
Series 8: Chiricahua Cave Creek Macrosite, 1987
Series 9: Chiricahua Portal Preserve, 1988, undated
Series 10: Chiricahua Turkey Creek, 1982
Series 11: Coffeepot Mountain Macrosite, 1987-1988
Series 12: Eagle Creek Natural Area, 1977-1986
Series 13: Empire Ranch Megasite, 1986, undated
Series 14: Escondido Falls, 1986
Series 15: Goodding RNA Extensions, 1987
Series 16: Guadalupe Canyon, 1979-1982
Series 17: Hartwell Canyon Preserve, 1986-1989
Series 18: Hassayampa River Preserve, 1986-1994
Series 19: Holbrook NE Site, 1981
Series 20: Jak Ranch, 1988
Series 21: Kino Springs, ca. 1978-1989
Series 22: Kiper Springs, 1979-1989
Series 24: McDowell Mountains, 1995
Series 25: Muleshoe Ranch Cooperative Management Area, 1884-1997
Series 26: Oracle State Park, 1973-1989
Series 27: Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Preserve, ca. 1965-1993
Series 28: Ramsey Canyon Preserve, 1953-1993
Series 29: Rio Yaqui Headwaters System, 1983
Series 30: Sabino Creek Macrosite, undated
Series 31: San Bernardino Ranch Site, 1979-1983
Series 32: San Francisco Peaks Site, 1988
Series 33: San Pedro River Biopreserve, 1973-1998
Series 34: San Rafael Valley Macrosite, 1980
Series 35: Santa Rita Experimental Range, 1978
Series 36: Tavasci Marsh Site, 1973-1993
Series 37: Tumamoc Hill Site, 1987-1990
Series 38: Vekol Valley Special Management area, 1988
Series 39: Volunteer Canyon-Smith Road Site, 1988-1990
Series 40: Waterman Mountains Site, 1986-1988
Series 41: White Canyon, 1989
Series 42: Whitewater Draw, 1991
Scope and Content Note
The Nature Conservancy in Arizona records (1884-1999) primarily documents the activities of the Arizona Chapter of The Nature Conservancy, an international non-profit conservation organization dedicated to the global preservation of natural diversity by identifying rare plants and animals and acquiring and protecting the land and water they need to survive. The materials in Subgroup 1 consist of the administration, correspondence, communications, program, and research and reference records of the organization. Subgroup 2 materials consist of site files for 42 sites, which may include one or more of the following subseries: administration, correspondence, ecology, history and archaeology, photographs and images, and protection and management records. Please note: dates reflect the subject content of the material.
Access Terms
Nature Conservancy (U.S.) Arizona Chapter -- Archives.
Conservation of natural resources -- Arizona.
Biodiversity conservation -- Arizona.
Wildlife conservation -- Arizona.
Wildlife refuges -- Arizona.
Buenos Aires National Wildlife Refuge (Ariz.)
Canelo Hills Cienega (Ariz.)
Bill Williams River National Wildlife Refuge (Ariz.)
Empire Ranch (Ariz.)
Hassayampa River Canyon Wilderness (Ariz.)
Muleshoe Ecosystem Management Plan.
San Pedro River Biopreserve.
Santa Rita Experimental Range (Ariz.)
Container List
- Subgroup 1: The Nature Conservancy in Arizona, Chapter Materials, 1962-1999, 6.70 linear feet (approximately 13,400 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
  The materials in Subgroup 1 consist of the administration (1970-1997), correspondence (1964-1999), communications (1968-1997), program (1975-1998), and research and reference (1962-1996) records of the organization. Administration files contain four subseries: Board of Trustees (1992-1994), Development (1970-1997), Operations (1990-1994), and Organizational History (1974-1994). Correspondence files contain two subseries: Chronological (1991-1994) and General (1964-1999). Communications files contain three subseries: Media-Public Relations (1990-1996), Newsletters (1968-1994) and Publications (1990-1997). Program files contain two subseries: Arizona Natural Heritage Program (1975-1988) and Volunteer Program (1989-1998). Research and Reference files contain six subseries: Federal Agencies (1975-1992), Maps and Aerial Images (1971-1992), News Clippings (1966-1979), Organizations and Institutions (1977-1996), Plans and Reports (1978-1994), and Subject (1962-1992).
  - Series 1: Administration, 1970-1997, 1.30 linear feet (approximately 2,600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains four subseries: Board of Trustees (1992-1993), Development (1970-1997), Operations (1990-1994), and Organizational History (1974-1994). Board of Trustees files include the meeting minutes and a list of officers, trustees and advisory council members. Development files document the financial planning, fundraising and strategic planning activities of the organization. Operations files include the fiscal management, budgets and planning documents. Organizational History files include the chapter bylaws, general information, manuals and directories from the national organization, and original office space documentation.
    - Subseries 1: Board of Trustees, 1992-1993
      - Board and Committee Meeting Minutes. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - List of Officers, Trustees and Advisory Council. 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Subseries 2: Development, 1970-1997
      - Financial Planning and Forecasting. 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Fundraising-20th Anniversary Marketing and Membership Campaign. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Fundraising-20th Year Oasis Fund Proposal and Financial Information. 1985-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Fundraising-Aravaipa Annual Barbeque Event. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Fundraising-Arizona Land Legacy Conservation Campaign General Information. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Fundraising-Arizona Land Legacy Conservation Campaign Packet. undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Fundraising-Ecotourism. 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Fundraising-Edward R. Steele Memorial Fund Proposal. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Fundraising-Pooled Income Fund and Fundraising Report. 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Strategic Plan-Concept/Issue Papers. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
      - Strategic Plan- "A Conservation Strategy for the 1990s", National Organization. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Strategic Plan- "Ensuring Our Short- and Long-Term Financial Stability", Arizona Chapter. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Strategic Plan- "Goals and Strategies for the 1990s", National Organization. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Strategic Plan-Goals, Report FY 1993. 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Strategic Plan-Goals, Report FY 1994. 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Strategic Plan-Goals by Program Area, FY 1994. 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
      - Strategic Plan-Interview Guide, Forms and Completed Forms. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Strategic Plan-Interviewed Strategic Planning Consultants. 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Strategic Plan-Process and Documentation Notebook, Plans and Memos. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24-28)
      - Strategic Plan-Reviews of Plan, Staff Retreat Results and Comment Forms. 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Strategic Plan-Summary 1981. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Strategic Plan-Summary 1982. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Strategic Plan-Summary 1984. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Strategic Plan-Strategic Vision Draft Priorities Project and Process Information. 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
      - Strategic Plan- "A Vision for the Coming Decade." 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Strategic Plan- "A Vision for the Coming Decade" -Report on Agency and Tribal Relations. 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Strategic Plan- "A Vision for the Coming Decade" - Supplement, Government Relations. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Strategic Plan- "A Vision for the Decade of the Nineties." 1994 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Subseries 3: Operations, 1990-1994
      - Fiscal-Budget Planning and Information, FY 1992. 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Fiscal-Budget Planning and Information, FY 1993. 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Fiscal-Budget Planning and Information, FY 1994. 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - Subseries 4: Organizational History, 1974-1994
      - Chapter Bylaws- The Nature Conservancy in Arizona. undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - General Information. undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - The Nature Conservancy-Calendar of Events. 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
      - The Nature Conservancy-Preserve Directory. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - The Nature Conservancy-Protection Manual. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6-11)
      - Original Office Space-Historic YMCA Building. 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Series 2: Correspondence, 1964-1999, 2.40 linear feet (approximately 4,800 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains two subseries: Chronological (1991-1994) and General (1964-1999). Chronological files include the monthly internal memoranda and external correspondence of the administration and staff of the organization. General correspondence includes both internal and external correspondence by name, subject, legislation, legislators or organizations.
    - Subseries 1: Chronological Files, 1991-1994
      - September 1991. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - October 1991. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      - November 1991. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - December 1991. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - January 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - February 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
      - March 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - April 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
      - May 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - June 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - July 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - August 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
      - September 1992. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
      - October 1992. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - November 1992. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - December 1992. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - January 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - February 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - March 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
      - April 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
      - May 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - June 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
      - July 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - August 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
      - September 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
      - October 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - November 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - December 1993. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - January 1994. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - February 1994. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - March 1994. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - April 1994. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - May 1994. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - June 1994. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - July 1994. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - August 1994. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - September 1994. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Subseries 2: General, 1964-1999
      - 200 X 2000 Site Conservation Plan. 1981-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
      - Chandler, William. 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Cochise County Plan. 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Land Protection and Management. 1998-1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Mount Graham Red Squirrel. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Legislation-Endangered Species Act Reauthorization. 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Legislation-Land and Water Conservation Fund. 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Legislation-National Biological Survey. 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Legislation-North American Free Trade Agreement. 1993-1999 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Legislators-DeConcini, Dennis. 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Legislators-Hayworth, J.D. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Legislators-Kolbe, Jim. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Legislators-Symington, Fife. 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
      - Legislators-Udall, Morris K. 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous. 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
      - Organizations-Arizona Native Plant Society. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Organizations-Audubon Societies. 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Organizations-Desert Botanical Gardens. 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Organizations-Ducks Unlimited, Inc. 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Organizations-Miscellaneous. 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Organizations-Southwest Hawk Watch. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Organizations-Wildlife Society, Arizona Chapter. 1980 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Steele, Edward. 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
      - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. 1964-1983 (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - Series 3: Communications, 1968-1997, .30 linear feet (approximately 600 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains three subseries: Media-Public Relations (1990-1996), Newsletters (1968-1994) and Publications (1990-1997). The Media-Public Relations files document legislative, general and press-related public relations activities. Newsletters includes regularly issued newsletters of The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter and the national organization. Publications include magazines and other published materials produced by the national organization.
    - Subseries 1: Media-Public Relations, 1980-1997
      - Briefing Packet for Arizona Delegation. 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Brochures and Visitor's Map and Guide. undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Press Coverage- Memorandum of Understanding and Accord with Bureau of Land Management. 1990-1996 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Press Coverage-Travel Writers Tour Articles. 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Voluntary Private Conservation Kit. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Subseries 2: Newsletters, 1968-1997
      - The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter. 1968-1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter. 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter. 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter. 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter. 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - "The One Conservancy" - National Office Bi-Weekly Newsletter. 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Subseries 3: Publications, 1990-1997
      - "Designing a Geography of Hope, Guidelines for Ecoregion-Based Conservation in the Nature Conservancy." 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "The Nature Conservancy Magazine." 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Series 4: Program Files, 1975-1998, 1.5 linear feet (approximately 3,000 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.
    This series contains two subseries: Arizona Natural Heritage Program (1975-1988) and Volunteer Program (1989-1998). The Arizona Natural Heritage Program files document the activities of this collaborative program between The Nature Conservancy, Arizona Chapter and The Arizona Game and Fish Department. Material includes: fiscal administration, operations, reports, correspondence, ecological resources, history, media and publicity, and protection and management of various ecological resources and sites. The Volunteer Program files document staff and volunteer activities including: coordination, correspondence, management, general information, recruitment, reports, recognition, and stewardship projects at various sites.
    - Subseries 1: Arizona Natural History Program, 1978-1998
      - Administration-Budget and Staffing Information. 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Administration-Contract Agreement between Arizona Game and Fish Commission and The Nature Conservancy. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Administration-Contract with Arizona Outdoor Recreation Coordination Commission. 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Administration-Expense Reports, Habitat Specialist. 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Administration-Fundraising Review Board. 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Administration-Habitat Specialist Contract Employee Position. 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Administration-Program Coordinator/Scientist Job Descriptions and Advertisements. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Administration-Operations Manual, Chapters 1-4. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Administration-Operations Manual, Chapters 5-7. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Administration-Operations Manual, Chapter 8- Appendices. 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Administration-Proposal for an Arizona State Heritage Program. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Administration-Report, Executive Summary on Past Progress and Future Needs. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Administration-Reports, Bi-Weekly. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Administration-Reports, Bi-Weekly. 1980 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Administration-Reports, Bi-Weekly. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Administration-Reports, Bi-Weekly. 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Administration-Reports, Bi-Weekly. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Administration-Reports, Fiscal and Budget Information. 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
      - Administration-Reports, Progress and Contract Information. 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence-Federal and State Agency Coordination. 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence-Fundraising. 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence-General. 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
      - Correspondence-Jenkins, Robert. 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence-Kolbe, Jim. 1981 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence-Letters of Support for ANHP. 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence-Moyseenko, Helmut. 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence-Non-Game Income Tax Check Off Legislation. 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Ecology- "Plant Communities of Arizona." 1983 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Ecology-Special Element Lists and Criteria for Listing Animals. 1980 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - History-Background Information and Correspondence. 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - History-National Heritage Policy Act. 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Media and Publicity-Brochure Sample. undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Media and Publicity-Newspaper Clippings. 1975-1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Media and Publicity-Press Releases. 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Media and Publicity-Radio and Television Segments. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Protection and Management-Arizona Potential Project Sites. 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Protection and Management-Element Ranking Procedures and Natural Diversity Scorecards. 1982 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Protection and Management-Intern Areas Project. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Protection and Management-Special Element Plant Abstract. undated (Box 6, Folder 3-8)
    - Subseries 2: Volunteer Program, 1989-1998
      - Coordinating Committee. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence-Sample Letters. undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - General Information. 1991-1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Handbook-Ramsey Canyon Preserve. 1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Information Package. 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Management System Instructions. 1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Manual-Volunteer Coordinator. 1995 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Manual-Volunteer Information System, VFILE. 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Projects-Aravaipa Canyon Preserve. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Projects-Bird Viewing Platform, Sierra Vista Wastewater Pond. undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Projects-Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Preserve. 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Projects-Site Stewardship Visits and Notes, Bingham Cienega Preserve. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Projects-Villa Restoration, Muleshoe Ranch Cooperative Management Area. 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Projects-Vinca Removal, Ramsey Canyon Preserve. undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Quarterly Volunteer Prospectus and Correspondence- Muleshoe Ranch Cooperative Management Area. 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Quarterly Volunteer Prospectus and List-Canelo Hills Cienega. 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Quarterly Volunteer Prospectus, Correspondence and Maps. 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Quarterly Volunteer Prospectus, Handbook and Correspondence-Patagonia-Sonoita Creek Preserve. 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Recognition and Awards-Ramsey Canyon Preserve. 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Recruitment-American Association of Retired Persons. 1989-1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Recruitment-Lists and Notes. 1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Recruitment-Procedure, Draft. undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Reports-Hours and Activities by Preserve. 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
      - Reports-Quarterly and Record of Hours Procedures. 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Stewardship Monitors Packet, Bingham Cienega Preserve. undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Series 5: Research and Reference, 1962-1996, 1.20 linear feet (approximately 2,400 items). Arrangement: alphabetical.